ALI HUSNAIN SHAH

.NET Developer

□ ahshah2211@gmail.com □ +923196989322

• Kharian, Pakistan

in linkedin.com/in/ahshah322/

PROFILE

.NET Developer with 3+ years of professional experience in designing, developing, and maintaining software applications using the .NET framework. Expertise in C#, ASP .NET MVC, .NET Core, Blazor, SQL Server, and PostgreSQL with a strong understanding of object-oriented programming principles. I possess a deep passion for technology and strong problem-solving skills with a commitment to continuous learning, and staying up-to-date with emerging technologies.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer, **Dolphin Digital OOH Media**

June 2022 – October 2023 J Plano, USA

Dolphin Digital is a Texas-based programmatic OOH media firm (Dlgital OOH Video and Audio ad network) with 1500 plus screens across the US.

- Improved performance by resolving more than 80 critical bugs in the company's products
- Development of server-side software using .NET Core 6/7. Blazor, and PostareSOL
- Designed front-end using Blazor component library like MudBlazor
- Implemented different tools to import and export data in Excel
- Applied fixes and enhancements to SQL scripts through PostgreSQL

.NET Developer, APKSoft

February 2022 – July 2022 | Kharian, Pakistan APKSoft is providing Information Technology services, Accounting services, Software Help Desks, and Support services worldwide.

- Managed 6+ website projects including business, ecommerce, and portal
- Enhanced the application's features to effectively fix the bugs and optimize the overall performance, reliability, and efficiency
- Designed web pages using HTML, CSS, CHTML, JavaScript, jQuery, Ajax, and page design and layout
- Utilized ASP .NET, ASP MVC, SQL Server, and Microsoft Visual Studio for development
- Build RESTful API's with ASP.NET Web API

EDUCATION

MASTER OF COMPUTER SCIENCE, **Government College University Faisalabad** 2019 - 2021 | 3.9/4

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE, University of Gujrat 2017 - 2018



HTML Web Development Crash Course ∂ 06/2018

CSS Web Development Crash Course ∂ 07/2018

LANGUAGES

English Urdu Punjabi

INTERESTS

Reading | Video Games | Cricket | Travel